Guide to the Rice University Photograph Files, 1910-2015 UA 363
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VII: Oversize Rice photographs (people, places, events, sports)
  - Individuals and Group Photographs (Oversize 1)
    - Images of men whose likenesses are carved on Lovett Hall Capitals (2 folders) (Oversize 1, Folder 26-27)
      - Theo. L. DeVinne - Photograph of bronze bust of DeVinne
      - Sir Isaac Newton (2)
      - William Thomson, Lord
      - Darwin, Charles (2)
      - Mendelejev, DImitri
      - St Paul (2)
      - Michelangelo, Raphael, Leonardo, Corregio (on one sheet)
      - Leonardo da Vinci (2)
      - Sophus Lie
      - Ferdinand de Lesseps (2) 1869
      - Christopher Columbus (2)
      - Thomas Jefferson
      - Samuel P. Langley
      - Joseph J. Thomson
      - Alfred R. Wallace
      - Michelangelo
    - John Boles (Oversize 1, Folder 28)
    - Richard Smalley (Oversize 1, Folder 29)
    - Sammy (owl mascot, not a costumed student) (Oversize 1, Folder 30)
    - R.A. Tsanoff (Oversize 1, Folder 31)
    - Harold Albert Wilson (Oversize 1, Folder 32)
    - Griffith C. Evans (Oversize 1, Folder 33)
    - Julian Huxley (Oversize 1, Folder 34)
    - First Board of Trustees, Rice Institute (E. Raphael, Capt. Baker, J.E. McAshan, W.M. Rice, Jr., B.B. Rice) (Oversize 1, Folder 35)
    - Brown, Mr. & Mrs. George R., and Alice Pratt (3) - see also box 7 folder 20 (Oversize 1, Folder 36)
    - George Rupp and Malcolm Lovett, 1989 (Oversize 1, Folder 37)
    - Students in and between classes, no date but circa 1950s - (9 poses) (Oversize 1, Folder 38)
    - Students - Space Science (Oversize 1, Folder 39)
    - Students - Studio Art (Oversize 1, Folder 40)
    - Students - Architecture (2 poses) (Oversize 1, Folder 41)
    - Students - RMC Courtyard (Oversize 1, Folder 42)
    - Students - Chemistry lecture hall stairs (2) (Oversize 1, Folder 43)
    - ICSA (3) (Oversize 1, Folder 44)
    - Shepherd School students on Herring Hall patio (2) (Oversize 1, Folder 45)
    - Rice Institute Engineering Society, 1916 (Oversize 1, Folder 46)
    - Archaeology dig in Mali (2) (Oversize 1, Folder 47)
    - Unidentified groups of people (2) (Oversize 1, Folder 48)
    - Baker College Cabinet meeting (Oversize 1, Folder 49)
    - Computer Services - Ken Kennedy and student (Oversize 1, Folder 50)
    - Norman Hackerman, et al inauguration 1971 (Oversize 1, Folder 51)
    - Students - 1988 football (Oversize 1, Folder 52)
    - Students (Oversize 1, Folder 53)
    - Students - fun time - 1935 (Oversize 1, Folder 54)
    - Bands, including Lee's Owls and others - 1921, 1925-1926, 1929, 1970s (Oversize 1, Folder 55)
    - ROTC (2 poses) undated (Oversize 1, Folder 56)
    - David Bailiff, Jarett Dillard, Chase Clement, 2009 (Oversize 1, Folder 57)
    - Students, 1954 (Oversize 1, Folder 58)
    - Rice Institute Class of 1916 (colored image) (Oversize 1, Folder 59)
    - Virginia McAshan Dupree, Edmund McAshan Dupree, Annie McAshan Kirby (Oversize 1, Folder 60)
    - Students, 1940s (Oversize 1, Folder 61)
    - Football, Ray Alborn, 2 players, ca. 1981 (Oversize 1, Folder 62)
  - Group Photographs cont. and Events (Oversize 2)
    - Girls in first class at Rice (?) - 1912 (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
    - James Baker Institute for Public Policy, group photo including Kissinger and Gorbachev - 1997 (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
    - Pre-Med Society - 1927 (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
    - Mino Badner & Gale Stokes (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
    - Cheerleaders, 1966 (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    - Track team, 1929 (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
    - Football team, 1913 (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
    - Archi-Arts Ball, 1941 - Theme Abstraxia (3 poses) (Oversize 2, Folder 8)
    - Baccalaureate (first) 1916, two photos: The Reverend Dr. Peter Gray Sears, Rector of Christ Church of Houston, first Baccalaureate speaker, 1916 (Oversize 2, Folder 9)
    - Commencement - (first) 1916, Chancellor Davil Starr Jordon of Stanford, speaker (4 views) (Oversize 2, Folder 10)
    - British Education Commission Visit, 1918 (some are identified incorrectly; check photo file drawer for more information) (Oversize 2, Folder 11)
    - Commencement - 1932; two photos (Oversize 2, Folder 12)
    - Baccalaureate/Commencement, 1954, Dr Peyton R. Williams, Pastor of Christ Church in Norfolk, Virginia, baccalaureate speaker. Dr K. E. Wallace Sterling, President of Stanford University, commencement speaker (3 envelopes) (Oversize 2, Folder 13-15)
    - Hiroshima Scientific Advisory Group Inspection trip, August 1947 (2 poses) (Oversize 2, Folder 16)
    - Homecoming - 1962 (Oversize 2, Folder 17)
    - May Fete - 1941 - 8 photos (Oversize 2, Folder 18)
    - Registration Day - Sept. 23, 1912 (3) (Oversize 2, Folder 19)
    - Walter Schirra Press Conference - October 1962 (2 poses) (Oversize 2, Folder 20)
    - Commencement - 1982 (Oversize 2, Folder 21)
    - Senior Day Picnic (n.d.) (Oversize 2, Folder 22)
    - Rice Engineering Show - 1928 (Oversize 2, Folder 23)
    - Commencement - Rice University 1992, 1993, 1994 (Oversize 2, Folder 24)
    - Visit by Gen. John Pershing; Feb. 5, 1920; with Dr. E. O. Lovett (water damaged photograph) (Oversize 2, Folder 25)
    - University Forum - TV program, including Hardin Craig, Eleanor Roosevelt, Delia Mares, January 1955 (Oversize 2, Folder 26)
    - Golden Anniv. - Rice University - 1994 (Oversize 2, Folder 27)
    - Formal Opening - Rice Institute - Oct. 12, 1912 (2 poses) (Oversize 2, Folder 28)
    - Garden Party following Commencement, 1921 (Oversize 2, Folder 29)
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower, President U.S., 1960, with George R. Brown, Carey Croneis, and others (Oversize 2, Folder 30)
    - John F. Kennedy and Kenneth Pitzer - September 12, 1962 (Oversize 2, Folder 31)
    - Economic Summit - 1990 (Oversize 2, Folder 32)
    - Economic Summit - 1990, Thresher staff and guests (Oversize 2, Folder 33)
    - "College Bowl" - 1966 (Oversize 2, Folder 34)
    - Class of 1924 50th anniversary (Oversize 2, Folder 35)
    - Rice - Texas Football game, 1950 (Oversize 2, Folder 36)
    - Pep parade, 1921 (Oversize 2, Folder 37)
    - Dedication of Autry House, 1921 (Oversize 2, Folder 38)
    - Sammy mascot stolen, 1917 (Oversize 2, Folder 39)
    - Snow on Rice campus, 1973 (Oversize 2, Folder 40)
    - Basketball and baseball (Oversize 2, Folder 41)
    - Malcolm Gillis and others (Oversize 2, Folder 42)
  - Sports and Individual Campus Buildings (Oversize 3)
    - Baseball Team - 1913 (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    - Football Squad - 1912 (3); 1913 (4); 1919 (1); 1920 (1); 1922; 1923; 1924 (2) (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    - Golf Teams - 1927-1930 (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    - Track Team - [1916-1917] and 1960 (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
    - Volleyball - Women (2) (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
    - Exterior Abercrombie Hall Engineering Lab Building - n.d. (2 folders) (Oversize 3, Folder 6-7)
    - Exterior Anderson Hall - March 10, 1950 (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
    - Exterior Chemistry Bldg - 10 photos: (3 n.d.; 7 marked "Rec'd 1925") (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - Exterior Fondren Library - 8 photos (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Interior Fondren Library - 27 photos - 1949? (2 folders) (Oversize 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Individual Campus Buildings cont. and Campus Buildings and General Campus Views (Box 4)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - 6 marked "Rec'd 1925"; taken by Tebbs-Knell, NY (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Perspective West Elevation drawing (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Cloisters - Architectural detail - n.d. (3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Exterior Mechanical Engineering Bldg - Power House & Campanile (rendering-2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Exterior RMC Cloisters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Exterior Autry House (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Sallyport (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Exterior Fondren Library (sepia) 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Exterior Physics Bldg (3) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Exterior Wiess Hall - Dormitory - 1950 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Architectural details (6), 5 views (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - rainbow, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - two glossy color prints (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall Construction (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - 1912? (2 views) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Spring - Late 80's & undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Exterior George R. Brown Hall (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall at dusk - Late 80's (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Exterior Jones College (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Interior Faculty Chamber - Lovett Hall (print and negative, different views) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Exterior Stadium (rendering) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Exterior Physics Bldg (n.d.) -2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Exterior South Tower Residential Hall; Men - c. 1910 (rendering) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Exterior South Tower Residential Hall; Men - perspective sketch & negative (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Exterior Abercrombie Hall - 1950 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Interior Abercrombie Hall; computer with Prof. Martin H. Graham (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Arch Details - Cloisters - 1937? (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - 1937? (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall - Arches - (3 views) (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Exterior Baker College & Mens Dorm (2) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Exterior Physics Bldg. detail (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Exterior Lovett Hall (snow) 1960 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Exterior Baker College architectural rendering 1911 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Interior Physics stairway (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Interior Wiess Hall - dorm building (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Interior Baker College Commons (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Interior Chemistry Bldg. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Baker & Will Rice Colleges, Lovett Hall, Chemistry Builidng, statue of Rice (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Residential Halls dormitory group (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Chemistry Bldg, Baker College, Lovett Hall (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Chemistry and Physics buildings (part of each) (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Cohen House and Lovett Hall (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Lovett Hall & Physics Bldg - n.d. (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Lovett Hall, Physics Bldg - general plan (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Physics Bldg, Lovett Hall - n.d.; Photograph by Townsend (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Physics Bldg, Men's Dorm - n.d.; Photograph by Townsend (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Baker and Will Rice Colleges, Field House and Mech Lab (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Physics, Lovett and Sewall (campus scene) (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Physics Bldg. and Campanile (roofs) (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Campus Buildings and General Campus Views cont. (Box 5)
    - Campus entrance gates - n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Wm Marsh Rice statue - by sculptor John Angel (3 photos of plaster cast) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Engineering Quad sculpture by Michael Heizer- Jan. 1985; 8 photos, entitled 45, 80, 190, George R Brown Memorial (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Campus - by Townsend - n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Cohen House fountain (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - General Plan rendering & negative - 1910 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Air Brushing by Leiper (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1927 - (5) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Aerial View - 1951-1957 - 2 views (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1929 ? (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1942 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1950 (2) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1915-1920 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Aerial View - Campus - 1992 (4) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Lovett Hall cloisters looking into quad- 1916 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Wm. Marsh Rice statue (2 views) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Lovett Hall interior door detail (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Bird's Eye View - Houston, TX with market hall & trolley (colored) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Dr. Lovett's office (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Aerial View - Rice University - Fall, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Lovett Hall Arcade - color (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Robert Ray Courtyard, Rice Memorial Center (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Brown Garden, Ley Student Center (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Main Entrance Gates, 1980's (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Library - Herring Hall (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Sallyport looking toward the Fondren Library (in fog) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Founder's room [Lovett Hall] c. 1990 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Campus Aerial View c.1998 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Campus Aerial View 1998 (3) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Campus Aerial View prior to 1950 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Campus aerial view, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Foggy walkway, main entrance (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Equipment with Tom Bonner, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Duncan Hall interior (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Rice Hotel (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Campus scenes (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Campus aerial view, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Campus aerial view, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Campus aerial view, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Jones School: Interior (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Herring Hall Renderings (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Individuals cont., groups cont., campus buildings cont. (Box 6-7)
    - Jess Neely (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Jimmy Carter, John Boles, and students, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Biology lab, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Michael Heizer sculpture installation, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sid Richardson College play, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lovett Hall cloisters, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lovett Hall with fireworks, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Lovett Hall with full moon, by Robert Flatt, ca. 2012 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Lovett Hall cloisters with students, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Lovett Hall drawing by Charles M. Capps (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Football game in old stadium, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Bluebonnet Bowl, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Rice vs. Texas football game, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Cheerleaders, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Lucky Sahualla and Rodney Burton, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Football post-game, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Volleyball, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Basketball (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Jay Knoblauh (baseball), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cheerleaders, Rice v. Navy (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Baseball players (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
    - Mikhail Gorbachev, Henry Kissinger, Rice Board of Governors, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Commencement, George Rupp at podium (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Campus aerial views (3) [prior to Cohen House] (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Campus aerial views (3), ca. 1937 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Campus aerial views (4), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Campus aerial view, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Campus aerial view, ca. 2002 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - General plan, Rice Institute, by Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Doorway, 1921 Campanile (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Turrets, 1920 Campanile (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - General Plan of the ...Rice Institute (1980) by Stephen Fox, proofs: Lovett Hall and reflecting pool, rendering (6), Jan. 1910; Lovett Hall, Mechanical Lab, East Hall (3), 1912, Dormitories (2); Physics Building and Lovett Hall cloisters, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - SS Rice Victory, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Harry Clay Hanszen (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - William V. McEnany (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Edgar Odell Lovett (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Kenneth S. Pitzer (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - William V. Houston (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Norman Hackerman (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Charles Dealey [?] (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Charlotte M. Allen, Augustus C. Allen - steel engravings (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Louis Pasteur, engraving (likeness on a capital on Lovett Hall) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Charles Garside, drawing (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Bishop Otto Dibelius (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Robert A. Millikan (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Student scholars and fellows, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Alice Pratt Brown and George R. Brown (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Opening ceremony delegates (5), 1912 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Rice band (2), 1925/26 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Rice football team, 1934/35 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Bobby May, Lance Berkman, Wayne Graham, College World Series, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Football, cartoon, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Fondren Library drawing by Buck Schiwetz (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Fondren Library (2) (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Physics Building, sepia print (2), 1921 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Lovett Hall cloisters, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Lovett Hall and Physics Building in snow (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Chemistry Building with students and faculty, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Stadium and fieldhouse, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Campus aerial view, 1949? (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Campus aerial view (3), 1937? (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Campus aerial view, 1946-47? (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Campus aerial view, 1956-05 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Campus area, William Ward Watkin Collection (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Formal opening poster of the Founder - William Marsh Rice, circa 1912 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous photographs
  - Academic Seal
  - Architectural Designs
  - Artificial heart components images, including an image of William Akers with components, 1966
  - Aurora I Satellite
  - Book Art - Fondren Library
  - Books by Larry McMurtry
  - Book Illustrations, Leonardo da Vinci
  - Books, Pamphlets, Ephemera
  - Cars
  - Cohen House, Place Setting
  - Continental Airlines Rice Poster
  - Courtlandt Place
  - Door Handles (Physics or Lovett)
  - Exhibits
  - "The Flying Owls"
  - Flyleaf (3 folders)
  - Friends of Fondren Gala Invitations Visuals
  - Fondren Library Chair
  - Guide for faculty and family sketches
  - A History of Rice University
  - House, Jean
  - Ionosphere Observatory at Abecibo
  - Javelin Probe
  - Laboratory Equipment
  - Landscaping
  - Laser Research
  - Library Exhibits
  - Lovett Book Reprint Images
  - Lovett's spectacles
  - Lunar Samples (Apollo XI)
  - Mace
  - [Rice] Memorabilia
  - Microelectronic Research 1972
  - Mules
  - Oil Derricks
  - Owl photos (on Rice Campus) - Robert Flatt
  - OWL Satellite
  - Owl-umni Quilt
  - Rationale Comic by David Chen
  - Sammy I Probe
  - Trees (campus)
  - Unidentified
  - Woodson Research Center brochure
- Series IX: Historical video
  - Rice Institute campus views video by William Kendall, Class of 1927, 1929